theoutbound.com 2019-05-13

# The Outbound Collective - Adventures Start Here

Thank you for using The Outbound. We are committed to providing you with the best experience possible. Please reference our **Privacy Policy** and **Terms of Use** to learn more. We welcome questions, concerns, and feedback about this policy at: [**support@theoutbound.com**](mailto:support@theoutbound.com).

* * *

**Effective Date: May 24, 2018**

#### 1\. The Outbound Collective and Your Information.

The Company collects information in order to provide better services to all of its users, customers, and partners. The information the Company collects, how that information is stored, and how that information is used is further described in this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy applies to all the information collected about you by or through the Company’s Website, [HTTPS://THEOUTBOUND.COM](https://theoutbound.com/) (the “Website”) and The Outbound mobile applications (“Mobile Apps”). The Website may contain links to other websites not controlled or created by the Company. The Company is not responsible for the privacy practices of those sites, and recommends that you review the privacy policies of each web site that you visit.

#### 2\. The Information Collected by the Company.

Information you provide directly. You are not required to provide information about yourself in order to visit the Website. However, if you register for an account to use the Company’s Services (the “Services”), you will need to provide the Company with personal information such as your first name, last name, location (city, state, country), email address, and a password. 

Information collected automatically. As you use the Website, the Mobile Apps, or any of our Services, the Company may collect or obtain certain information about you automatically, including: 

  * Your browser type and operating system;
  * Your Internet Protocol (IP) address;
  * Sites you visited before and after visiting the Website;
  * Date and time of your visit;
  * Web pages and advertisements you view and links you click on within the Website;
  * Unique identifiers for your device, operating system and mobile network including carrier name and phone number and application version number;
  * Information collected through cookies, web beacons, and other technologies;
  * Information about your interactions with email messages, such as the links clicked on and whether the messages were opened or forwarded;
  * Standard server log information;
  * Geolocation; and
  * Project-related data.

#### 3\. Information you choose to provide.

  * **Additional Profile Information.** You may choose to provide additional information as part of your profile on The Outbound Collective (such as birth date, gender, links to social media profiles, personal websites, images, and a personal description). Some of this information as indicated in your Account settings is part of your public profile page, and will be publicly visible to others, and indexable by search engines.
  * **Content Submission.** You may choose to participate in our community by providing content on the Website and Mobile Apps including but not limited to locations, stories, adventures, photos, reviews, lists, bookmarks, likes and follows.
  * **Other Information.** You may otherwise choose to provide us information when you fill in a form, conduct a search, update or add information to your Account, respond to surveys, post reviews, participate in promotions, invite friends, or use other features of The Outbound Collective Services.

If you provide information on behalf of someone else (or someone else provides information on your behalf), the person providing the information must have consent to do so from the person whose information is being provided. “Information” means information that can be used to distinguish or trace your identity, either alone or when combined with other information that is linked or linkable to you. Certain parts of the Services may be offered in conjunction with another company. If you provide information in such cases, both the Company and the other company(ies) may receive the information collected and use the information according to each company’s respective privacy policy and agreement with you.

#### 3\. How the Company Uses Your Information.

The Company desires to provide the best services to all its users, and uses your information to deliver these services. Your information will also be used for the following reasons: 

**_Maintain and Improve the Company’s Services._** The information you provide is used to ensure the Services are working as intended, such as troubleshooting issues you report. The Company will also use your information to make improvements to the Website, Mobile Apps, and Services, and to improve or enhance Company’s support.

**_Develop New Services._** The Company uses the information collected to add to the Company’s general knowledge base in order to help develop new content and services.

**_Provide Personalized Services._** The Company collects, compiles and stores analytical and project-related data to monitor and provide feedback and notifications to you related to the products and services you use.

**_Provide Relevant Updates._** The information collected allows the Company to provide you with relevant updates including the following: 

  * Send information, content, promotional or marketing communications which we think may be of interest to you and in accordance with your communication preferences;
  * Send information to you regarding changes to our Terms of Service, Privacy Policy (including the Cookie Policy), or other legal agreements;
  * Meet legal requirements.

We may, from time to time, contact you on behalf of external business partners about a particular offering that may be of interest to you. In those cases, we do not transfer your Personal Information to the third party.

You may, at any time, opt-out of email communication by updating your communication settings in the Settings section of the Company’s services.

**_Use of Credit Card Information._** If you give us credit card information, we use it solely to check your financial qualifications and collect payment from you. We use a third-party service provider to manage credit card processing. This service provider is not permitted to store, retain, or use information you provide except for the sole purpose of credit card processing on our behalf.

**_Security of your Personal Information._** We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your Personal Information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. We secure the Personal Information you provide on computer servers in a controlled, secure environment, protected from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. All Personal Information is protected using appropriate physical, technical and organizational measures.

**_Social Media Features._** Our Website and Mobile Apps include Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share This button. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our sites, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Website and Mobile Apps. This Privacy Policy does not apply to these features. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy and other policies of the companies providing them.

**_External Websites._** Our Website and Mobile Apps provide links to other websites. We do not control, and are not responsible for the content or practices of these other websites. Our provision of such links does not constitute our endorsement of these other websites, their content, their owners, or their practices. This Privacy Policy does not apply to these other websites, which are subject to any privacy and other policies they may have.

**_Third Party Marketing._** Where you have provided consent, we share your information, including personal information, as described at the time of consent when you participate in promotional activities conducted by The Outbound Collective, partners or third parties.

**_Measure Performance._** The Company also uses the data for analytics and measurements to understand how the Services are used. For example, the Company analyzes data about your visit to the Website to do things like optimize the products and improve our content, marketing and service offerings.

**_Aggregation._** The Company may compile or derive statistical information from your data to be aggregated with the statistical information compiled or derived from other visitors to the Website or Mobile Apps. However, such statistical information will be anonymous and non-identifiable to you. The Company aggregates statistical information to better serve its users and to improve the manner in which it conducts business.

**_Business Transfers._** The Company may share your information in connection with a substantial corporate transaction such as a merger, consolidation, asset sale, or in the unlikely event of bankruptcy.

**_Protect Users._** The Company uses the data to help improve the safety and reliability of its Website and Mobile Apps, and to prevent potentially prohibited or illegal activities.

#### 4\. Cookies and Similar Technologies

**_Cookies_** Cookies are small data text files and can be stored on your computer’s hard drive or your Device (if your Web browser permits). The Outbound Collective, its affiliated websites, and Mobile Apps use cookies for the following general purposes: 

  * To help us recognize your browser as a previous visitor and save and remember any preferences that may have been set while your browser was visiting our site. For example, if you register on our site, we may use cookies to remember your registration information, so you do not need to log into our site each time you visit.
  * To help us customize the content, experience, and advertisements provided to you on our websites and Mobile Apps and on other websites across the Internet. For example, when you access a web page, a cookie is automatically set by us, our service providers, or our partners to recognize your browser as you navigate on the Internet and to present you with information and advertising based on your apparent interests.
  * To help measure and research the effectiveness of features and offerings, advertisements, and email communications (by determining which emails you open and act upon).

The Help portion of the toolbar on most browsers should tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable most types of cookies. Please note that if you refuse to accept cookies, you may not be able to access some of the Services offered on our Website.

Our Website may also use Web beacons (also known as clear gifs, pixel tags or Web bugs), which are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, that are placed in the code of a Web page. The Company or our partners may use Web beacons to monitor the traffic patterns of users from one page within our Website to another, to deliver or communicate with cookies, to understand whether you have come to our site from an online advertisement displayed on a third-party website, and to improve site performance. The Company may also allow our service providers to use Web beacons to help us understand which emails have been opened by recipients and to track the visitor traffic and actions on our site. This helps us measure the effectiveness of our content and other offerings.

**_Single Sign-On._** You can log into our site using a Single Sign-on (SSO) service like your Facebook account. This service will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us such as your name and email address. Such services may give you the option to post information about your activities on the Website or Mobile Apps to your profile page to share with others within your network.

**_Advertising._** We partner with third party ad networks to either display advertising on our Website or Mobile Apps, or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our ad network partners use cookies and Web beacons to collect information about your activities on this and other Websites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests.

#### 5\. Data Transfers.

The Company may use servers around the world, and your information may be processed outside the country you are located. While data protection laws vary among countries, the Company will apply the same protections described in this policy regardless of where the processing occurs.

#### 6\. Your Choices Regarding Your Data.

You can visit and use the Website without directly providing any personal information; however, as described above, some information may automatically be collected or may be requested so you can take advantage of certain features. In addition, you must provide personal data in order to register for an account or use the Company’s Mobile Apps and Services.

You have rights concerning your data. These rights include: 

**_Managing, Reviewing and Updating Your Data._** The Company strives to ensure your data is accurate. In the event you become aware of an error or inaccuracy in your data, you may notify the Company at the email and/or address provided below. You have the right to access your data at any time in order to receive information on how your data is being used and for what purpose.

**_To Unsubscribe from Our Communications._** You may unsubscribe from our marketing communications by clicking on the "unsubscribe" link located on the bottom of our emails, updating your communication preferences, by sending us email us at support@theoutbound.com, or postal mail to the address below, Attention: Privacy. You cannot opt out of receiving emails related to their account, legal notices, or payment related information.

**_To Unsubscribe from Our Partners’ Communications._** In the event that you give your consent to share your personal information with our partners, our partners are solely responsible for their own marketing emails and other communications; we cannot unsubscribe you from their communications. You can unsubscribe from our partners’ marketing communications by clicking on the "unsubscribe" link located on the bottom of their emails, or by contacting them directly.

**_Exporting, Removing and Deleting Your Data._** You have the right to export a copy of your data if you want to back it up or use it for another service. You also have the right to delete all or any portion of your data by contacting the Company at the address provided below. In some cases, the Company may retain data for a limited period when it is needed for a legitimate business or legal purpose. You will find the ability to export your data and delete your account within Settings on the Website and Mobile Apps.

#### 7\. Privacy by Design.

The Company will store and process your data only as necessary to provide the products and services requested. The Company is committed to continuously protecting your information and works hard to protect your data from unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure, or destruction. Some of the actions and safety measures taken by the Company to protect you include: 

  * Using encryption to keep your data private;
  * Reviewing its information collection, storage and processing practices, including physical security measures; and
  * Restricting access to the data to Company employees, contractors and agents who need that information in order to process it. Anyone with access is subject to strict confidentiality obligations and may be disciplined or terminated if they do not comply with these obligations.

#### 8\. Privacy Protections for Children.

The Website and the Company’s Services are intended for users age 16 or older. Users under the age of 16 are not permitted to use the Website or create an account without parental consent. The Company does not knowingly collect or process the personal data of individuals under the age of 16.

#### 9\. Changes to This Privacy Policy.

The Company may update this Privacy Policy from time to time. The Company will not reduce your rights under this Privacy Policy without your explicit consent. If the Company modifies this Privacy Policy, it will update the “Effective Date” at the top of this page and such changes will be effective upon posting. The Company will also keep prior versions of this Privacy Policy in an archive for your review.

#### 10\. Questions.

If you have questions regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact the Company at the email or mailing address below:

**_Email:_**  

**_Mailing Address:_**  
The Outbound Collective  
1288 Columbus Ave, #201  
San Francisco, CA 94133
